<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Pawel Sobala</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Pawel Sobala</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Viewing source code for a function</title>
      <link>/blog/viewing-source-code-for-a-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/viewing-source-code-for-a-function/</guid>
      <description>RationaleYesterday, I wanted to take a look at the source code of cor.test() function in R. I did what I usually do in such case - namely, I called the function and I expected to see the code straight way.
cor.test## function (x, ...) ## UseMethod(&amp;quot;cor.test&amp;quot;)## &amp;lt;bytecode: 0x000000001463dcb8&amp;gt;## &amp;lt;environment: namespace:stats&amp;gt;Unfortunately, I didn’t get the code but instead I recieved information that it comes from a S3 generic function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating R to 4.0.0 - challenges</title>
      <link>/blog/updating-r-to-4-0-0-challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/updating-r-to-4-0-0-challenges/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}New R Version!On the April, 24th a new R version was released - version 4.0.0. The complete list of changes/bug fixes/etc. in the newest version is available here. In my opinion, following changes are the most crucial ones:
A new syntax is offered for specifying _raw_ character constants similar to the one used in C++, where r ... can be used to define a literal string.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calculating YTD return of EM curencies</title>
      <link>/blog/analysis-of-em-curencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/analysis-of-em-curencies/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}IntroductionThe goal of this short article is to calcuate the returns of Emerging Markets (EM) currencies in 2020.The main observation is that all of those currencies since mid-Febraury 2020 (Coronavirus 2020 Financial Crisis) significantly weakened in comparison to EUR or USD.The question is also, was there any curency that performed better in EUR than in USD?
Specification of CurrenciesThe currencies that are going to be analyzed as a part of this analysis has been chosen arbitrarly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Section - &#39;Books&#39;</title>
      <link>/blog/new-section-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/new-section-books/</guid>
      <description>I added to the blog a new section called “Books” - available from the toolbar above. Currently, there are books/articles that are related to programming or to different tools that can be used in R. I read those books/articles and I recommend them. This section will be updated step by step. In the future most likely by books that are related to programming in Python/Julia.If you know about any other interesting books about programming in R, please let me know in comments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>