<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pawel Sobala</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Pawel Sobala</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Pawel Sobala and I am a data science enthusiast. My interests encompass (but are not limited to) the statistical programming language R, data analysis, financial markets, cyber insurance and football. For my professional experience, please refer to my LinkedIn page.
In addition to the blog entries I am posting regularly on Twitter (some tweets are in polish though).
You can reach me via social media on Twitter and GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of the tq_get() function</title>
      <link>/blog/analysis-of-the-tq-get-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/analysis-of-the-tq-get-function/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}IntroductionOne of the most important parts of any analysis including financial or economic data is getting the data. Of course it is possible to download data diretcly from the Internet. However, in some cases there are limitations when downloading data. For example, only last 5 years of data is available, maybe the frequency is not suited to the needs of the analysis or it is cumbersome to update data on a regular basis in the code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideas</title>
      <link>/ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ideas/</guid>
      <description>In preparation or in my mind are articles related to the following topics:
 Analysis of the tq_get() function Implementating the Cyber Insurance Pricing Model Performing a Gold/Silver ratio analysis Analysis on relation between ISM, stock returns, [inspiration] Analysis of webscraped data from Willhaben and Allegro Modelling Stock Market using Kohonen Map, [idea] Creating a R course, [inspiration] Creating a R package based on some codes that I wrote Financial analysis including machine learning/deep learning techniques Sharing experiences on participating in a Kaggle competition DALEX package Tidy Text Mining with R &amp;hellip;   The author reserves the right to publish those articles in no particular order.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>