<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pawel Sobala</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Pawel Sobala</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating R to 4.0.0 - challenges</title>
      <link>/blog/updating-r-to-4-0-0-challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/updating-r-to-4-0-0-challenges/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}New R Version!On the April, 24th a new R version was released - version 4.0.0. The complete list of changes/bug fixes/etc. in the newest version is available here. In my opinion, following changes are the most crucial ones:
A new syntax is offered for specifying _raw_ character constants similar to the one used in C++, where r ... can be used to define a literal string.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calculating YTD return of EM curencies</title>
      <link>/blog/analysis-of-em-curencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/analysis-of-em-curencies/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}IntroductionThe goal of this short article is to calcuate the returns of Emerging Markets (EM) currencies in 2020.The main observation is that all of those currencies since mid-Febraury 2020 (Coronavirus 2020 Financial Crisis) significantly weakened in comparison to EUR or USD.The question is also, was there any curency that performed better in EUR than in USD?
Specification of CurrenciesThe currencies that are going to be analyzed as a part of this analysis has been chosen arbitrarly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books</title>
      <link>/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/</guid>
      <description>Below is a list of programming books/articles that I recommend. This list will be updated.
 General programming in R:
  R Packages Efficient R programming Advanced R R for Data Science   Modelling in R:
  Forecasting: Principles and Practice Tidy Text Mining Explanatory Model Analysis Explore, Explain and Examine Predictive Models Applied predictive modelling Caret Package Tidy Models Parsnip - A tidy interface to models Statistical Inference via Data Science Natural Language Processing in Python (In Polish)   Tools with R:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Section - &#39;Books&#39;</title>
      <link>/blog/new-section-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/new-section-books/</guid>
      <description>I added to the blog a new section called “Books” - available from the toolbar above. Currently, there are books/articles that are related to programming or to different tools that can be used in R. I read those books/articles and I recommend them. This section will be updated step by step. In the future most likely by books that are related to programming in Python/Julia.If you know about any other interesting books about programming in R, please let me know in comments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to find packages on CRAN from RStudio</title>
      <link>/blog/how-to-find-packages-on-cran-from-rstudio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/how-to-find-packages-on-cran-from-rstudio/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}MotivationWhen writing a new blog post on the assessment of the quality of fitted Self-Organizing Map (SOM) to the data I stumbled upon a problem on how to find all R packages that are related to a particular subject on CRAN. In particular, my problem was to find all packages that might contain any items related to the assessment of SOM.
Librarian PackageAfter goggling for a while I found the library(librarian) package which contains a function browse_cran() to search package names and descriptions within CRAN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating quickly a R Package</title>
      <link>/blog/creating-quickly-a-r-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/creating-quickly-a-r-package/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}MotivationFor my next post on Self Organizing Maps I started researching different ways on how to determine the quality of a map. Firstly, I found this article entitled “Evaluating Self-Organizing Map Quality Measures as Convergence Criteria”, which contains a couple of different measures on approaching the problem. Alongside it, I found R code in this thesis, which was used in the aforementioned article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self Organizing Map for WSE</title>
      <link>/blog/self-organizing-map-wse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/self-organizing-map-wse/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}This is a first post from a series of articles on Self Organizing Maps (SOM). The next post will cover the topic regarding analyzing the SOM and its quality.
IntroductionThe purpose of this short article is to create a Self Organizing Map (SOM) using the Kohonen R package, which could help understand the whole Warsaw Stock Exchange (WSE) market based on financial and economic data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Pawel Sobala and I am a data science enthusiast. My interests encompass (but are not limited to) the statistical programming language R, data analysis, financial markets, cyber insurance and football. For my professional experience, please refer to my LinkedIn page.
In addition to the blog entries I am posting regularly on Twitter (some tweets are in polish though).
You can reach me via social media on Twitter and GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of the tq_get() function</title>
      <link>/blog/analysis-of-the-tq-get-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/analysis-of-the-tq-get-function/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}IntroductionOne of the most important parts of any analysis including financial or economic data is getting the data. Of course it is possible to download data directly from the Internet. However, in some cases there are limitations when downloading data. For example, only last 5 years of data is available, maybe the frequency is not suited to the needs of the analysis or it is cumbersome to update data on a regular basis in the code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideas</title>
      <link>/ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ideas/</guid>
      <description>In preparation or in my mind are articles related to the following topics:
 Analysis of the tq_get() function Implementation the Cyber Insurance Pricing Model Performing a Gold/Silver ratio analysis Analysis on relation between ISM, stock returns, [inspiration] Analysis of web scraped data from Willhaben and Allegro Modelling Stock Market using Kohonen Map, [idea] Analysis of Self-Organizing Map quality Creating a R course, [inspiration] Creating a R package based on some codes that I wrote Financial analysis including machine learning/deep learning techniques Sharing experiences on participating in a Kaggle competition DALEX package Tidy Text Mining with R &amp;hellip;   The author reserves the right to publish those articles in no particular order.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>